HIEU MINH NGUYEN

☑ hieunguyenvn98@gmail.com · 🕻 (+84) 9067659838 · 🗘 therealhieu · 🛅 nguyenminhhieu

Ambitious and enthusiastic Data Engineer with 2 years of experience in developing data pipelines and working with cloud technologies. I am passionate about building data products, solving technical and business problems, and utilizing both open-source and proprietary technologies to deliver the best solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Career break

Aug 20223 - Present

- Addressed health concerns and achieved full recovery.
- Continuously engaged in self-learning and coding exercises.

Fossil Group, Inc

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Data Engineer

Nov 2021 - Jul 2023

- Engineering:
- Engaged directly in Data Platform to do ETL, data validation and monitoring.
- Developed an ingestion API in Rust for mobile apps and watch apps to send data to Kafka. Some Rust crates used: actix-web, kafka-rust.
- Was a core member to rebuild Python-based Data Platform in Rust. Performance was improved by 10x in production. Typical Rust crates used: arrow2, polars, duckdb-rs, tokio, tower, pyo3.
- Technologies: Kafka, S3, Redshift, BigQuery, Airflow, Spark, Great Expectations, Grafana

Analytics:

- Worked closely with Product team to define app tracking events and build dashboards.
- Technologies: Data Studio, BigQuery, Redshift, Athena.

Fossil Group, Inc Data Engineer Intern

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Feb 2020 - Aug 2020

Designed data warehouse, implemented data transformation and built analytics dashboards.

Technologies: Firebase, BigQuery, Redash, Athena, MongoDB,

Google Data Studio

Agilsun Co., LTDWeb Developer Intern

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

EDUCATION

HCMVNU- University of Information Technology

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

2016 - 2021

GPA: 9.1/10

Thesis: Constructing knowledge graphs with triple

Bachelor of Engineering, Information system

extraction techniques

Ben Tre High School for the gifted

Ben Tre, Vietnam

High School Diploma, Mathematics

2013 - 2016

GPA: 8.9/10

SKILLS

Data Engineering: Python, Rust, SQL, Airflow, Kafka, Spark, AWS (S3, SQS, Athena,

Redshift).

DevOps: CI/CD, Docker, Kubernetes.